# Christian Gonzalez

# Android Developer

· +44 7379 240609

□ contact@chgonzalez.com

chgonzalez.com

in linkedin.com/in/chgonzalez9

# Summary

A self-taught young developer from Spain, with a strong passion for coding. Coding websites and Android Apps for the past 6 years, managing the frontends and backends and using different coding languages, like html, kotlin, JavaScript and more, while also expanding my knowledge by doing online courses.

## Skills

#### Technical Skills

#### Soft Skills

- Mobile Development: Kotlin, Native Android, MVVM, Critical thinking Google Maps, JUnit, Retrofit, OKHttp, Room, Glide, • Problem solving Koin..

  - Team work
  - · Organization skills
- Web Development: Html5, CSS, Javascript, Wordpress,
- Development Environments: Android Studio, Atom, Visual Studio Code, IntelliJ IDEA, Bootstrap Studio
- · Others: Git and Github, Firebase, AWS

# Work experiences

Sous Chef | London 2021 - 2022

#### Tonkotsu

- · Mentoring and training new entries
- Led team while working under pressure
- Flexibility and adaptability to role change
- Daily carrying out manager duties
- Problem-solving

## General Service Assistant | Spain

2017 - 2020

#### Ilunion

- · Ability to make independent decisions and judgments on routine procedural issues
- Ability to maintain and manage equipment, machinery, and supplies
- Strong interpersonal and communication skills
- Customer service

# Personal Projects

# Nasa Asteroid app

Asteroid Radar is an app to view the asteroids passing near Earth, detected by NASA. Users can view all the detected asteroids given a period of time with data such as the size, velocity, distance to earth and if they are potentially hazardous.

· Technology used:

MVVM architecture, Binding Adapter, Room, LiveData, Navigation, WorkManager, Retrofit, OKhttp, Moshi, picasso, TalkBack, RTL

https://github.com/chgonzalezg/NASA\_asteroid

#### **Location Reminder app**

It's a simple To-do List app. The Location reminder will notify users to perform an action when they are at a specific location

· Technology used:

Google Maps, Firebase, Geofence, Koin dependencies injection, MVVM, JUnit

https://github.com/chgonzalezg/LocationReminder

#### Political Representatives app

A Political Preparedness app that delivers civic data to end users via the app. Using the Google Civic API users can see their representatives and the upcoming elections.

## · Technology used:

MVVM, Lifecycle, RecyclerView, Location Service, Google Clvic API, OKHttp, Retrofit, Glide, DataBinding, MotionLayout, ROOM

https://github.com/chgonzalezg/representativesApp

# Education

# Android Kotlin Developer Nanodegree by Google

2021 - 2022

#### Udacity

- · Kotlin languague
- Android UI components, Gradle build and Implement data persistence
- Animation with MotionLayout
- Testing
- -Certificate: https://confirm.udacity.com/3AZMLLHH

# C1B3RWALL ACADEMY: Blockchain and Cryptocurrencies

2021

#### C1b3rWall

Coordinated by the University of Salamanca and the National Police, It's a course that discusses the latest developments in cybersecurity, blockchain technology and everything that converges in the field.

# Android Basics Nanodegree by Google

2020 - 2021

#### Udacity

- Java, and XML language
- The basics of object-oriented programming
  Networking in Android, HTTP. JSON parsing and threads
- -Certificate: https://graduation.udacity.com/confirm/VLHAKAUN

#### **English Academy** 2019

EF International Language Campus

Web Development 2019

# FreeCodeCamp

- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript

**High School** 2011 - 2017

IES Juan Antonio Zunzunegui

# Languages

**Spanish** Native speaker

**English** 

**Basque** Native speaker

Links

https://github.com/chgonzalezg